ADAM D'COSTA

TRAINEE WEB DEVELOPER

BRISTOL, UK

TECH STACK

HTML

CSS/SCSS

JAVASCRIPT

REACT

JAVA

FIREBASE

GIT/GITHUB FLOW

SKILLS

Buying

Customer Service

Excel

Merchandising

Full clean UK driving license

INTERESTS

Reading

Nature

Walking

Sports

Food

Profile

After 8 years of working as a book buyer and bookseller I've decided to retrain and lead my career in an exciting new direction. A desire to learn new skills and reapply my customer-focused, flexible skillset developed in my previous roles has led me to undertake a 12-week intensive web development course at _nology with a view to moving into a new industry as a web developer.

Experience

Foyles Bookshop

AREA COMMERCIAL SUPPORT

Sept 2019 - July 2021

- Support shop teams through effective buying, ordering, communication, and training to ensure consistent commercial offers across all departments.
- Working closely with the store management team on specific projects and to drive improvements – for example planning and implementing a re-lay of the flagship store in order to drive sales of new and bestselling titles whilst also setting merchandising standards.
- Act as a conduit for communication between head office, store management, operations teams and the shop floor.
- Work closely with the Campaigns Manager to plan the window display schedule, from new title displays through to seasonal peak range selections. Help to feed in to and implement campaigns at the store level.

HEAD OF PROMOTIONS

Sept 2017 - Sept 2019

- Responsible for planning, co-ordination and maintenance of the key Front of House and departmental display areas at Charing Cross Road, as well as ordering and negotiating margin.
- Working to ensure each key display area hits weekly benchmarks and using data to inform decision making when changes are necessary.
- Outlining a strong, title-driven promotional plan, that supports the store and company's overall strategy and works in line with key publishing dates and seasonal peaks.
- Working on projects with external and internal stakeholders to bring together cross-platform promotions.
- Working closely with internal stakeholders to ensure we are maximising sales opportunities and keeping standards to a level that the customer would expect from a destination store in Central London.

Education

London Metropolitan University September 2009 - June 2012

BA(Hons) Illustration – First Class Honours

Stroud College September 2008 - July 2009

Foundation Diploma in Art and Design – Distinction

KLB School – Wotton-under-Edge September 2001 – July 2008

A Levels - Fine Art(A), Graphic Art (A), Maths(C), French-AS(B). GCSEs - 4 A* grades, 8 A grades